MARIA CECÍLIA ROMÃO SANTOS

+55 (32) 98509-1907 - ceciliaromao@gmail.com / cecilia.romao@estudante.ufjf.br

PROFESSIONAL RESUME

Very attentive, dedicated, and organized, with the ability to absorb and develop new knowledge, identify problems, and develop solutions to optimize the work routine. Professional prepared for the challenge of performing new functions and activities with flexibility.

Discipline to perform my role with excellence, whether in person or remotely, and having a good interpersonal relationship. Collaborative, empathetic, and innovative profile, sense of urgency, transparency, and favorable to giving and receiving feedback for continuous improvement.

PROFESSIONAL BACKGROUND	
since 04/2022	Software Engineer Trainee – Cheesecake Labs (Remote)
	Trainee Program for Software Engineering and FullStack Development of Web and Mobile
	Applications.
11/2021 - 03/2022	Analyst Developer – Hospital Maternidade Therezinha de Jesus (Juiz de Fora/MG)
	Responsible for generating and managing company database reports. Development and management of TOTVS processes. Experience with JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Git, Bootstrap,
	SQL, TOTVS Fluig, and RM line.
08/2021 - 11/2021	Intern – Centro de Gestão do Conhecimento Organizacional / UFJF (Juiz de Fora/MG)
	Professional Academic Training Program. Adaptation project to the new standards of accessibility and technologies in the UFJF Institutional Sites.
10/2019 - 01/2020	Condominium Administration – Condomínio Residencial Jardins do Eldorado
	Condominium Administration.
02/2016 - 06/2019	Supervisor – BrasilCenter Comunicações (Juiz de Fora/MG)
	Hired initially as Customer Service Representative – Incoming Billing (Small and Medium
	Enterprises), and later as Specialized Customer Service Representative - Anatel. After one
	year at the company, I was approved in the internal selection process for Apprentice Leader,
	working as a supervisor.
11/2014 - 01/2015	International Sports Sales Executive – THG Sports (Rio de Janeiro/RJ)
	The Marcus Evans Company, THG Sports, provides tickets and corporate hospitality
	programs at global sports events. I worked as a corporate sales executive, identifying and
	prospecting for potential customers.
11/2010 - 11/2012	Legal Intern – Praxair / White Martins Gases Industriais Ltda. (Rio de Janeiro/RJ)
	Supervised Internship in the Legal Sector, working in the civil, environmental, criminal,
	labor, administrative, corporate, real estate, contracts, bidding, tax, and financial areas.
06/2010 - 10/2010	Legal Intern – Amil Assistência Médica Internacional S/A (Rio de Janeiro/RJ)
	Supervised Internship in the Litigation and Regulatory Legal Sector. Legal Monitoring,
	Elaboration of pieces, defenses, petitions, forensic practices related to the regulatory agency
0.7/2.01.0	of the supplementary health sector, ANS.
05/2010 - 06/2010	Legal Intern – Dr. João Bosco Won Held (Rio de Janeiro/RJ)
	Civil, Criminal, and Labor Area. Follow-up of processes, first service, and preparation of
02/2010 06/2010	initial petitions.
02/2010 - 06/2010	Legal Intern – XII Juizado Especial Cível (Rio de Janeiro/RJ)
	Mandatory Supervised Internship
	First Service and Preparation of Initial Petitions

EDUCATION _

in progress Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Universidade Federal de Juiz de Fora – Juiz de Fora/MG

graduation expectation: 12/2024

07/2015 Law Degree (Bachelor)

Universidade Estácio de Sá – Rio de Janeiro/RJ

CERTIFICATIONS

- Legal Argument, Fundação Getúlio Vargas (2012)
- Reform in the Criminal Procedural Code, Fundação Getúlio Vargas (2012)
- The Judge and Ethics, Fundação Getúlio Vargas (2012)
- Management of the Judiciary, Fundação Getúlio Vargas (2012)
- Tripartition of Powers, Curso R2 Direito (2011)
- Strategic management, Laureate Digital / Business School São Paulo (2020)
- Introduction to the topic of Leadership, Fundação Getúlio Vargas (2020)
- Management with People, *Universidade Estadual do Maranhão* (2021)
- Occupational Psychology, Universidade Estadual do Maranhão (2021)
- Healthy leadership: transforming people and companies, *PUC/RS* (2022)
- Hour of Code Basics Concepts of Computer Science, *Code.org* (2013)
- E-mag Developer Web accessibility, Escola Nacional de Administração Pública Enap (2021)
- Data Science and Data Intensive Scalable Computing, Global July Program 2021 UFJF (2021)
- Cache Efficient Computing, Global July Program 2021 UFJF (2021)
- Full stack web development (JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, React, SQL, Node.js, API Rest), Cubos Academy (2021)
- TOTVS Fluig Dev Start, *TOTVS* (2021)
- Processes management BPM/ECM Essentials, TOTVS (2021)
- Processes management BPM/ECM Intermediate, *TOTVS* (2022)
- Processes management BPM/ECM Advanced, TOTVS (2022)
- BIRT reports, *TOTVS* (2022)
- Emotional Intelligence 2.0, *Conquer* (2022)
- Fluig x RM Integration, *TOTVS* (2022)
- Portal Development with WCM, *TOTVS* (2022)
- Full stack web development, Alpha EdTech (2022 em andamento)

LANGUAGES -

- Spanish: intermediate reading, writing and conversation.
- English: fluent reading, advanced writing, fluent conversation.
 TOEIC score: 910 (june/2013)

OTHER JOB EXPERIENCES -

10/0010 00/0016	
12/2012 - 02/2016	English Teacher – Wizard Bangu (Rio de Janeiro/RJ)
03/2012 - 09/2012	English Teacher - Wizard Santa Cruz (Rio de Janeiro/RJ)
03/2012 - 02/2013	English Teacher - Yes!- BSM Bangu Escola de Idiomas Ltda. (Rio de Janeiro/RJ)
05/2007 - 12/2010	Volunteer – Primeira Igreja Batista de Vila Aliança (Rio de Janeiro/RJ)
	Volunteer work teaching English to children and adolescents in a favela in Rio.
02/2010 - 03/2010	English Teacher – Red Balloon – VMSB Curso de Inglês Ltda (Rio de Janeiro/RJ)
08/2008 - 07/2010	English Teacher / Educational coordinator - Wizard Santa Cruz (Rio de Janeiro)
04/2007 - 07/2008	English Teacher - Yes! - CJL Instituto de Idiomas Ltda. (Rio de Janeiro/RJ)
06/2007 - 07/2007	Volunteer – Jogos Pan-Americanos Rio 2007 (Rio de Janeiro/RJ)
	Bermuda Olympic Committee Assistant
	Translation and Interpretation

Translation and Interpretation.